welcome to the listening Time Podcast
hey everybody this is Connor and you're
listening to episode
10027 of The Listening Time Podcast
thank you all for listening today my
voice is a little bit weak because I'm a
little bit sick uh so I'm sorry about
that I appreciate you bearing with me I
appreciate your patience by the way
speaking of patience patience uh this is
the topic of today's episode patience so
I want to talk about this today uh and
talk about some different situations in
which patience is
required uh it's necessary so I think
this will be a good topic for all of us
because I think that pretty much
everybody has room for improvement when
it comes comes to Patience by the way we
use that phrase room for improvement
this just means that you have space to
improve you are not perfect there are
still improvements that you can make so
we all have room for improvement when it
comes to patience so this should be a
good topic for today's episode and uh
hopefully it will inspire all of us to
be a little bit more patient in our
everyday lives and uh hopefully that
will help us out so that's what we'll
talk about today remember that you can
sign up for my us conversations podcast
if you feel ready to start practicing
with real conversations between native
speakers in each episode I talk to
someone from a different part of the
country from the the us and we talk
about a bunch of different topics and
you get to learn a lot about the us our
culture different
topics uh these conversations are really
interesting and we speak naturally and I
provide the transcript for you so you
can follow along and you also have the
definitions of new words and phrases
that you might not know that we use
during the conversation so if you're
interested in that the link is in the
description below this episode that's
patreon.com USC conversations and if you
want my Advanced podcast episodes uh if
you want to practice with me speaking at
normal speed then make sure to sign up
for my membership the link is also in
the description below if you become a
listening Time family member you get two
new Advanced episodes every month and if
you're a Spanish or a Portuguese speaker
check out my ebook if you want to read
fiction in English those links are down
below as well and as always if you like
this podcast please give it a five-star
rating and write a review and share it
with anyone else you know who's learning
English all right let's get started our
are your ears ready you know what time
it is it's listening
time okay let's talk about patience so
first of all I need to mention that I'm
not the most patient person in the world
uh this is an area in which I need to
improve a lot uh I am willing to admit
that uh because I'm not the most patient
person and I really want to improve in
this area I uh look at my wife for
example she's more patient than I am and
I try to learn from her because uh there
are times when we're both dealing with
the same
situation and she is patient and calm
and I'm more agitated uh the word
agitated means that you are uh bothered
and anxious uh for some reason so I
might be agitated and yet she's
perfectly fine and we're dealing with
the same issue so uh I can see that
other people uh have more patience than
me sometimes s and I really want to
improve in this regard I need to improve
and I try to do so every day so I'm not
talking uh from the perspective of
someone who has tons and tons of
patience uh I'm talking as someone who
needs to improve in this area so what
are some different situations in which
we need to be patient the first one that
comes to mind is when we're sitting in
traffic by the way we use that phrase
sitting in traffic uh when uh we talk
about being in your car and you're in
traffic it's moving very slowly or
sometimes it's not moving at all we say
that you're sitting in traffic so this
is the first situation that comes to
mind when I think of patience because
it's a very common occurrence and for me
it's one of the most frustrating
situations I hate being in traffic it's
uh one of the worst things I'm sure a
lot of you agree with me about this so
if we're not patient then traffic can
really bother us it can really Annoy Us
and sometimes it can ruin your day
because you allow your mood to uh be
negatively
affected by the fact that you have to
wait in traffic so this is something
that we want to avoid because we can't
control traffic it's completely outside
of our control and if we get bothered uh
by
traffic this doesn't help us right we
can't do anything to change the
situation to make the traffic suddenly
go away we have no control over that so
I don't think it's worth it to uh lose
our
patience uh to lose our cool and get
really angry when we're stuck in traffic
there's no benefit to that by the way
when we say that you lose your cool this
means that you lose your patience and
you snap you get mad you get really
frustrated right so we don't want to
lose our cool just because traffic is
bad so that's the the first thing that
comes to mind because I'm guilty of this
sometimes when I'm stuck in traffic I uh
get
frustrated and uh I let it affect my
mood but I definitely shouldn't do this
so that's one that I need to work on
another situation in which we need
patience is when we're dealing with a
difficult person we've all been there we
all know how this is by the way when I
say that we've all been there what I'm
saying is we've all been in this
situation so we've all been there we've
all had to deal with a difficult person
uh in some situation or another and uh
sometimes we can lose our cool and we
can allow this situation or this person
to frustrate us to the point where we
act uh differently we don't do what we
should do or maybe we talk in a way uh
that isn't the best so I'm sure you know
what I'm talking about uh sometimes we
have to deal with difficult people and
it's important to not let them uh bring
us down to the level where we're getting
really mad uh for no good reason right
sometimes we get angry at another person
uh for a legitimate reason obviously I'm
not talking about that I'm not talking
about being angry with a person because
they've done some horrible thing they've
committed some Wicked crime crime or
something like that that's not what I'm
referring to I'm referring to situations
where a person is just hard to deal with
and you need to be patient with them so
that can happen in the workplace that
can happen uh just in public at stores
with employees at certain companies in a
lot of
situations so dealing with these people
requires patience and it's good to uh
act patiently in these situations
because sometimes we are the difficult
people sometimes I am the difficult
person or you are the difficult person
and other people have to deal with us so
I think that we should uh be patient
with people because sometimes we need
people to be patient with us so it goes
both ways and another situation in which
we need to be patient is listening to
people you might not think of this as a
situation that requires patience but it
does because people talk and we should
try to listen and sometimes people talk
a lot or their story that they're
telling takes a long time and you can
get bored or you can start to uh get
distracted or you can stop listening for
example and we sometimes lose patience
uh when we have to listen to other
people talk because everybody loves to
uh talk about what they want to talk
about people like to uh be the ones to
share things and talk about things but
not everybody likes to listen and that's
a more important skill is being able to
listen when other people talk to you and
that's something that we should all uh
try to improve on and make sure that
we're patient and we are listening to
people and we are genuinely caring about
what other people are saying and if you
do this if you demonstrate patience in
this situation you're going to have
better relationships people are going to
like you more you're going to have
fewer uh argu arguments maybe uh the
other person is going to feel more uh
cared about for
example and you'll have better
communication overall so I think that we
should all practice uh with uh just
being able to shut our mouths and listen
to other people speak and not just
immediately try to uh uh talk and
interrupt and say what we want to say we
should let the other person finish uh
before we uh start giving our opinion
about something for example so that's
another situation another time when we
need to be patient is when we're
learning a language this is very
relevant to all of you and to me because
I'm a language learner learning a
language takes a long time I constantly
get questions from people uh asking
about their language learning
process and usually they express
frustration that they aren't
improving uh fast or they feel stuck or
they feel like their progress is uh not
what they want it to be they feel like
they have a problem they ask me
questions and they frame the question
kind of like uh saying that there's
something wrong with them why aren't I
improving how I should be uh I have a
problem with this what's wrong with me
what should I be doing differently I
constantly get questions like this and
these are legitimate questions I'm not
saying that these aren't good questions
however what I want to say is the vast
majority of the time uh when people ask
me this
question uh it's not uh like these
people are uh studying in the complete
wrong way and they're wasting their time
time and they need to completely
change uh everything about their
language learning routine it's not that
usually they are just uh advancing
slowly and they don't realize it and
they don't realize how long it takes to
learn a language okay let me give you an
example of my language learning process
I've been speaking Spanish
for over a
decade not a year or a couple years not
five years not eight years no I've been
speaking Spanish for over 10 years over
a decade now okay my wife is a Spanish
speaker uh she only speaks to me in
Spanish okay I lived in Mexico for six
years my whole life was in Spanish for 6
years and yet today over 10 years later
I'm still in the process of learning
Spanish not actively I don't actively
study Spanish however I'm constantly
learning new things new words there are
things that I don't understand uh there
are things that I
misunderstand there are things that I
need uh people to repeat because I
didn't get it and I make mistakes all
the time all of this is uh what I deal
with and I've been speaking Spanish for
over a decade I've lived in the country
for many years my wife only speaks in
Spanish to me and yet I'm still
improving I still make mistakes I still
have an accent I still don't sound
anything like a native speaker Etc so
just know that learning a language takes
a really long time in terms of getting
to a very high level of course you can
reach an intermediate level uh in a
pretty short period of time if you
dedicate a lot of hours to it uh and you
can even reach an advanced level in a
relatively short period of time
depending on your motivation and how
many hours you're dedicating to it
however when uh your goal is to become
really good at a
language that is inevitably going to
take a long time when I say that
something is inevitable what I'm saying
is that it's unavoidable so there's no
way to avoid this if you want to reach a
really high level in English then that's
going to take a really long time okay
that's just how it is we need to be
patient and similarly another situation
in which we need to have patience is
when we are trying to achieve a goal uh
learning a language is one goal that's
one example
but when we want to achieve any goal we
need patience if you want to lose weight
that's not going to happen tomorrow
right uh you can't just expect that to
happen in 24 hours you need to stick
with it for a certain period of time
before uh you actually see these results
by the way the phrase stick with it just
means that you continue doing something
so you need to stick with it and be
patient and eventually you'll see
results but not
overnight the word overnight refers to
from one day to the next you're not
going to see results in just one day you
need to have a little more patience than
that or if your goal is to learn some
new skill maybe you want to learn a
programming language or something like
that that's not going to happen
overnight you need patience you need to
accept that this is going to take some
time and uh eventually you'll reach your
goal right if you stick with it but
patience is necessary when we set goals
and we want to to achieve these goals
and another situation that requires a
lot of patience is when we're going
through government
processes this is probably the worst one
for me this is the thing that is the
most frustrating and tests my patience
the most when I am going through a
government process
and the government takes a long time to
do the process and uh respond to me or
to do what they need to do this can be
really
frustrating I need to have more patience
when it comes to this because this is
inevitable we all deal with these
processes uh we all live in country
that have uh governments that are uh not
efficient and not very uh well-run and
are not uh the best institutions with
the best customer service and all of
that all of us are in this situation
regardless of uh which country you live
in so we need to have patience and know
that these processes are going to take a
while and uh we can't do that much to
influence this uh so when my wife was
going through the immigration process to
live in the US this took a long time
this took multiple years so this was
something that required a lot of
patience and at times it felt like it
was never going to end but of course it
did and we got through the process and
uh everything is okay now but during
that period it was hard to have patience
sometimes and that was something that
really taught me to uh just wait and to
not allow things that I can't control to
uh negatively impact my life and my uh
daily life and my my mood uh I needed to
kind of uh not focus on this process and
just live my life be patient and wait so
that was a big one and one more
situation that I wanted to mention
probably the most important one uh the
most important
situation in which we need patience is
when you are parenting when you have
kids when you have kids your level of
patience is tested uh in a way uh unlike
anything else so you're dealing with
small people
humans that have not learned to act
properly behave well communicate
effectively they don't know this yet
they don't have these skills especially
at Young ages so if you don't have
patience this is going to be very hard
for you you're going to deal with a lot
of situations in which you uh are
annoyed or irritated or you feel
desperate because you know uh how
something uh needs to be but your kid
doesn't they don't know this uh or they
do the opposite or they uh do a lot of
things that can possibly uh irritate us
and affect our mood and they can cause
us to uh lose our cool sometimes and we
need to be careful with this and we need
to exercise patience and to really
understand that kids need instruction
and discipline and they need time they
need time to learn these things and to
learn how to behave properly learn how
to communicate uh learn how to express
their feelings in a good and uh normal
way they need time before they can do
all of this effectively so we can't
expect them to just be born with the
these skills that's simply not reality
and as a parent uh patience is necessary
you need to understand that uh these
processes take a long time uh these kids
will need a long time before they really
learn all these lessons and uh they can
do things the way that you can do them
as an adult so for me that's uh probably
the most important situation in which
patients is uh definitely required so
those were some different situations but
there are plenty of others I hope this
episode was interesting for you and
hopefully it got you thinking a little
bit about your uh patience levels and
maybe it can and inspire all of us to be
a little more patient and if you feel
ready to practice with real
conversations between native speakers
then make sure to sign up for my us
conversations podcast the link is in the
description below this episode uh you'll
love this these conversations are really
interesting and it's great practice for
your listening so make sure to sign up
that's patreon.com SL USC
conversations and if you want to join my
membership and get my specialized
training for your listening and your
pronunciation and my Advanced podcast
episodes then make sure to join my
membership that's
patreon.com
listeningtime and if you're a Spanish or
a Portuguese speaker and you want to
read fiction in English then check out
my eBook The Links are also down below
and if you like this podast
I'd really appreciate it if you could
share it with anyone you know who's
learning English that really helps me
out and please give it a five-star
rating and write a review all right
thank you for listening to this episode
and I'll talk to you on the next episode
of listening
[Music]
time